MICHAEL SAVAGE

Co. Monaghan, Ireland

michael.savage7@mail.dcu.ie github.com/michaelssavage linkedin.com/in/michaelssavage

PERSONAL PROFILE

2021 BSc (Hons) graduate with a 1.1. Experience in Java, Python, React, and TypeScript. Strong interpersonal skills with the ability to communicate confidently with individuals at all levels shown by working part-time during study and succeeding with numerous teams.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tools & Technologies - Python, Flask, React, TypeScript, Vite, Java, Spring Boot, Firebase, Bootstrap, Git, REST APIs, JSON, PYQT5, BeautifulSoup, Docker

EXPERIENCE

Jaguar Land Rover, Clare

June 2021 - Present

Software Developer

- Successfully completed the Graduate Program completing valuable technical and soft skills.
- Earned the Professional Scrum Master™ I (PSM I) certificate and facilitated different meetings.
- Acted as Buddy for a new intern and helped answer any questions they had during their placement.
- Led some key decisions made in regards to linting, project structure, testing, and code coverage.
- Was given Great Performer for my end of year performance review.

Peaky Blinders Gastropub, Monaghan

March 2019 - March 2020

Bartender and Floor Staff

- Fast-paced environment that demanded the learning of new skills quickly.
- Provided friendly high standard customer service as bartender and floor staff.
- Acted as a mentor for new staff which helped develop my communication skills
- Deputised for manager and given managerial responsibility by cashier balancing, and ensuring bar opening and closing times.
- Took the lead in stressful shifts by delegating work and cooperating with other staff.

Westenra Arms Hotel, Monaghan

May 2016 - March 2019

Bartender

EDUCATION

Dublin City University (DCU)

2017 - 2021

BSc (Hons) in Computer Applications - 1.1

Modules Included - OO Analysis & Design, Data Structures & Object Oriented Programming, Software Testing, Concurrent & Distributed Computing.

Technologies Used - Python, PYQT5, Spacy, Sci-kit Learn, Pandas, Docker, BeautifulSoup

Projects

<u>TastyTravel</u> - Implemented an Android app that helps users meet for food or drink. Developed an algorithm that found locations based on isochrones and interpolation. Employed HTTP requests to get relevant location information from Google APIs.

Online B2B Ordering System - Developed a client-server application using a Python Flask backend and a React frontend. Data was sent through a REST API and data storage was handled with locks.

<u>Java Space Mission Controller</u> - Designed a Java program that uses a master-worker design pattern to replicate space missions (threads) being sent off by a mission control class while handling shared resources

Final Year Project

<u>eMot</u> - Developed an application that uses data extraction, natural language processing, emotion classification, and machine learning to judge the sentiment of textual material being read online by a user. User metrics are then graphically represented in a PYQT5 interface.

St.Macartan's College, Monaghan

2011 - 2017

Leaving Certificate: 470 points

AWARDS

- **2022** Successfully completed the Jaguar Land Rover Graduate Program.
- 2022 Earned the Professional Scrum Master™ I (PSM I) certificate.
- 2021 Won best group research paper in 4th year on the topic of Global Software Engineering.
- 2019 Won the Monaghan Senior Football Championship with Clontibret O'Neills.
- **2019** Successfully completed the DCU Mentoring Programme 2018-2019 and was shortlisted for best Reflect Portfolio as part of the programme.
- 2017 Div.1 League, Div.1 Cup, and Nutty Crust Tournament winner with Armagh Rugby Club u18's.
- 2015 Represented Ulster Club Rugby u18s by starting at no.11 in the Inter-Provincial series.
- 2014 Danske Bank Rannafast GAA Cup final winner with St. Macartan's College.

ACHIEVEMENTS & VOLUNTEERING

- 2020 Climbed Carrauntoohil.
- **2019** Successfully chosen to attend the *'JPMorgan Chase Code Commit'* networking event to take part in team coding competitions and network with company software engineers afterwards.
- 2018 Coached 30 children of ages 8-12 intermediate rugby skills at a summer camp in Monaghan RFC.
- 2018 Organised trips and fundraisers for DCU Rugby as part of the events committee in 1st Year.